Finding aid for the Paul Monette papers, 1945-1995 LSC.1707
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 1: Journals, 1971-1992
  - Journal Twelve, 15 May 1989-20 June 1991; 160 pages; 20.5 x 26.5 cm (Box 60, Folder 2)
    The twelfth journal includes a number of notable features, perhaps most significantly the rough drafts of two poems: "Committing to Memory" and an unpublished poem entitled "D-Day." Written in the front flyleaf of the journal is the Hindu mantra "om namah sivayah" and two phone numbers. Discoloration is extant between the front flyleaf and the first page of the journal indicating that an item once inserted there is now missing. On the journal's back flyleaf, Monette drafts his epitaph: "Paul Monette / 1945-199 / LIES HERE AT LAST." Taped to the inside of the back cover is a photograph of Monette and Craig standing in front of the Washington Monument and the AIDS Quilt. A phone number is written beside this photograph. Toward the end of the journal are notes Monette writes in preparation for Craig's memorial service. The last three pages of the journal contain three lists from the 1989 and 1990 holiday seasons in which Monette catalogs the presents he purchases and the cards he sends.
  - Journal Thirteen, 26 June 1991-29 July 1992; 160 pages; 19 x 24.5 cm (Box 60, Folder 3)
    In the last of his thirteen journals, dating from June 26, 1991 to July 29, 1992, Paul Monette primarily records notes on emerging AIDS research and explores his feelings about Winston Wilde, his third and final significant other.
    The thirteenth journal, the shortest of the thirteen, begins by referring to an unspecified accident that leaves Monette feeling "disabled" and increasingly preoccupied with the state of his health. In the first entry, Monette additionally mentions completing the sixth chapter of his National Book Award Winning memoir Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story (1992) and remarks that his friends—who he lists as Gary (also referred to as "GB"), Victor Brown, and Charles Jordan (also "Chuck")—are " freaked out or Twilight Zoned" by the AIDS crisis. For the most part, the journal registers notes Monette takes either at community forums on the biomedical dimensions of the crisis held by Dr. Mark Katz at Fairfax High School in Los Angeles and by the Delaney AIDS Research Enterprise or during his therapy sessions with Sam Dubreville. In the latter set of these entries, Monette works to transform his growing sense of fragility and mortality into a renewed zest for living as well as address what he views as childish and manipulative tendencies in Winston (also "WW," "W," and "Winnie"). Monette explores his feelings about Winston's sexual fetishes and proclivities as well. In the penultimate passage of the thirteenth journal, which was written two and a half years before his eventual death from AIDS-related complications, Monette writes, "I like being alive; I like living—but one tires of the threat upon one's life and the cloudy future" (page 20; original underlining).
    Monette filled up less than 30 pages of the 160-page journal. Pages 24 through 155 of the journal, as well as pages 158 and 159, are left blank. However, tucked between pages 58 and 59 is a receipt that seems to have been for the journal itself and wedged between pages 116 and 117 is a stub from a United Airlines ticket (from Los Angeles to New York). Also, a few notable features appear at the back of the journal. On pages 156 and 157, Monette composes the rough draft of the third movement of his poem "Committing to Memory." He dates its composition as occurring "Xmas '91." On the final page of the journal, Monette catalogs the names of those to whom he sends Christmas cards and for whom he buys presents during, presumably, the 1991 holiday season.
- Series 2: Biographical
  - Subseries 2.1: Family and Friends
    - Family/Records: Better Homes & Gardens Baby Book: Prenatal to Six Years., 1945. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Scope and Contents note
      Paul Landry Monette from Fran Fead, October 16, 1945. With entries by PM's mother, 1945-1955. Baby and school photographs laid in back of book. Baptism.
    - Family: Mother and Father: Notes: Primarily enclosing gifts, begin, ca. 1977. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      One is a poem (PM to his mother?). Dates are per PM's guess.
    - Friendships: Cesar Albini: Correspondence: Letter (?)., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: From Star(?)., n.d. (1970s?). (Box 49, Folder 1)
      Three folders filed as Letters--Friends transferred to UCLA, 1995.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: Letters from Richard Howard., January 11 and July 30, no year.; Each is typed, signed. (Box 49, Folder 2)
      Early to mid 1970s(?). January 11 mentions wanting a poem for American Review, but not as long as No Witnesses; July 30 about poem The Onlooker.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: Letter from Kay Boyle., February 27, 1971. (Box 49, Folder 3)
      Was perhaps lecturing and PM gave her manuscript to read(?).
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: Primarily signed with first names, clippings, poems, etc., Primarily early 1970s. (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: Letters signed with first names, lists of names, copies of others' poems, etc. (?)., early 1970s (Box 49, Folder 5)
      Kept in a folder labeled: Mrs. Carroll, but seemingly nothing to do with the novel.
    - Friendships: Stuart Curran: Correspondences, 1986 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Friendships/Travel: Craig Rowland: Italy: Scrapbook of photographs., November 2-11, 1987. (Box 37, Folder 1)
      Cover (laminated?) with hotel receipts, Italian money, labels, etc.
    - Friendships: Craig Rowland: Correspondences: (poem)., August 12, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      1 typescript of poem, recto and verso, 1 letter holograph. Letter and clipping or interview with PM (New York Native).
    - Friendships: Craig Rowland: Correspondences: With Christian Draz and John (?)., 1990.; Photocopies. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Friendships: Craig Rowland: Memorial Items: Eulogy written by PM., 1991.; 3 leaves. Typescript. (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Contains the history of their friendship.
    - Friendships: Craig Rowland: Correspondences: Letters from Rudy Kikel, one enclosing manuscript., April-September 1992; December 27, 1993.; [26 leaves total]. (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Manuscript is of poems by RK based on journals of CR: 19 leaves. Typescript (wp?).
      General note
      See photographs in Roger Horwitz papers, Box 42 (folder 2-3).
    - Friendships: Craig Rowland: Correspondences: Note from CR's mother., September 14, 1992. (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Describes CR's memorial service.
    - Family: Mother: Memorial Items: Obituary clipping., February 23, 1990. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Family: Mother: Memorial Items: Condolence letters., 1990. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Friendships: Victor Kenyon Brown: Correspondences Received, April 24, 1990-1991 and n.d. (Box 4, Folder 20)
      Primarily undated cards, note cards.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received, 1986-1989. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Madeleine Follain, Kennedy Fraser, John Kane, David Schorr.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received, 1990-1991. (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Guru Ma Jaya, Tony Smith, John Vasconcellos, etc.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received, 1992. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Otis Charles, Cobey Black, Gay Block, Malka Drucker, Richard Ide, Tony Smith, Brother Toby.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received, 1993. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Otis Charles, John Kane, Michael Lassell, Brother Toby, etc.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received, 1994. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Otis Charles, Sally Jackson, David Roman, David Schorr, Tony Smith, Stuart Timmons, Joey Terrill.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Star Black, Barbara Horwitz, Tim Miller, Tony Smith.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: Various Writers: Malcolm Boyd - Mark Thompson, Ayofemi Folayan, etc., 1987-1994. (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Sidney Blumenthal, Michael Denneny, Katherine V. Forrest, David Groff, Boze Hadleigh, Larry Kramer, JD McClatchy, Ethan Mordden, Paul Reed, etc.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: Prominent Persons, 1987-1994. (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Peter Bunnell, Perry Falk, Barbara Horwitz, Linda Hunt, Guru Ma Jaya, Daphne Manerkin, Tim Miller, Ned Rorem, Rob Volpe, etc.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: Enclosures of poetry, stories, etc., 1988-1994. (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Nisa Donnelly, Malka Drucker, Boze Hadleigh, Eloise Klein Healy, Raphael Kadushin, Rudy Kikel, J.D. McClatchy, David Roman, David Schorr and Jon Zasler.
    - Family: Correspondences, 1992-1993. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: Writers, Prominent Persons, 1990-1994. (Box 49, Folder 6)
      Includes letters from: Christine Downing, Eric Garber, Larry Goldstein, Herbert Hamsher and Judith Light, Richard A. Isay, Michael Kearns, Ma Jaya.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: Writers, Prominent Persons, 1993, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 7)
      Includes letters from: Anna Quindlen, Steven Saylor, John Weiners, Gary Wills, Terry Wolverton.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received, 1993-1995. (Box 49, Folder 8)
      Includes letters from: Gay Block, Otis Charles, Diana Cobbold, Michael Denneny, Malka Drucker, Madeleine Follain, Jerome Gold, Eloise Klein Healy.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received, 1989-1994. (Box 49, Folder 9)
      Includes letters from: Andrew Holleran, Herbert Hamsher? Sally Jackson, Tony Kushner, Michael Lassell, Toby (Brother Tolbert McCarroll).
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received, 1990-1994. (Box 49, Folder 10)
      Includes letters from: Ian McKellen, Tim Miller, Ned Rorem, Tony Smith, Urvashi Vaid, Bruce Weber, Bohdan Zachary.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: Signed with first names only., 1993-1995, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: Primarily from friends, but also last letters from persons PM had written to, and some fan mail not related to specific books, but to wishes for PM., 1994-1995. (Box 49, Folder 12)
      Includes letters from: Sascha Bittner, Tony Smith, Winston Wilde (cards).
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: (?)., December 21, 1994 (Box 49, Folder 13)
      From Diana Cobbold, enclosing manuscript based on Cesar Albini (?).
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: (?)., 1993-1994 (Box 49, Folder 14)
      With enclosures of readings, etc.
    - Correspondences, Between Monette and Martin Duberman, 1993 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received and Memorabilia: found in PM's desk (folder 1 of 2). (Box 50, Folder 5)
      Enclosing early reviews (photocopies), etc. Reviews: Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll, The Gold Diggers, The Long Shot, letter about Just the Summers [PM play, cf. Borrowed Time], flyer for reading.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received and Memorabilia: found in PM's desk (folder 2 of 2). (Box 50, Folder 6)
      Letter about The Carpenter at the Asylum, copy of letter to Rand Schrader from Dear Abby, map of Delos, etc.
    - Pets: Puck: Collar and tags. (Box 50, Folder 10)
      Cf. Last Watch of the Night.
    - Pets: Puck: Health, etc.: Items pertaining to Puck. (Box 50, Folder 11)
      Veterinarian's and euthanization records.
    - Friendship/Recording: Musical Copies: Hesse lieder, Psalm 100, conducted by J. Brody(?)., Cassette recording. (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Friendships/Recording: Ron Lema: My Man [recording]., Cassette tape. (Box 51, Folder 9)
      Inscribed April 9, 1991: For Paul, Ron Lema.
    - Friendships: Correspondences Received: From Dan Luckenbill and David S. Zeidberg, UCLA Library Department of Special Collections., February 5, 1995. (Box 52, Folder 1)
      Delivered to Winston by dl at, it turns out, approximately the time of PM's death.
    - Joseph Wittreich's Monette Collection: Photographs, Late 1980s (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Joseph Wittreich's Monette Collection: "Love Alone" Poem Drafts, circa 1987 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Joseph Wittreich's Monette Collection: Newspaper Clippings, 1988-1997 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Joseph Wittreich's Monette Collection: Correspondences, 1987-1996 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Joseph Wittreich's Monette Collection: Publicity Buttons, circa 1993 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Joseph Wittreich's Monette Collection: CUNY Honorary Degree Materials, 1993-1994 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Joseph Wittreich's Monette Collection: Literary Criticism, 1993 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Joseph Wittreich's Monette Collection: Memorial Service Materials, 1985-1995 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Joseph Wittreich's Monette Collection: Event Fliers, 1988-1997 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 2.2: Education and Teaching
    - Education: Elementary--Junior High: Report cards., 1951-1958. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      From first grade to seventh grade (no fifth grade report card). One school savings book for fourth grade.
    - Education: Elementary--Junior High: School savings program passbooks., 1953-1954. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Education: Religion: Holy Communion: Book and certificate., 2 items. (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Education: Religion: Bible given to PM., 1960. (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Education: Religion: Book of Common Prayer: PM's (?)., late 1950s (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Education: Religion: Bible given to PM: with note from PM's mother., 1981. October 16, 1981. (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Education/Records: Phillips Academy: Scholarship certificate., July 1961.; 1 card. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Announouncement of Award Mr. Paul Landry Monette ... for the school year 1961-62 John Cornell Scholarship (signed) Headmaster.
    - Education/Honors: Yale: Letter from Lady Bird Johnson (First Lady)., April 22, 1966.; 1 leaf. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Congratulating PM on chairing A Festival for the Arts.
    - Education/Honors: Yale: Poetry prize, dean's list, etc., 1967.; Clippings. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Dean's list Senior Year. Poetry prize in Senior Year(?). Carnegie Teaching Fellowship at Yale for year after graduation. Cf. Becoming a Man.
    - Education/Travel: Yale: Letters to parents from Europe., June-August 1966.; 33 items, 41 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      On scholarship to Cambridge.
    - Education: Yale: Senior thesis: The Hero of In Memoriam., April 1967.; [3] p.l., 72, [2] leaves. Typescript. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      To William C. DeVane and Lewis P. Curtis, my great teachers. Mentions Harold Bloom's comments.
    - Education/Honors: Yale: Award. Letter from Beekman C. Cannon (Master, Jonathan Edwards College, Yale University)., May 10, 1967.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      A College Fellows award for writing.
    - Education/Records: Yale: Diploma from Jonathan Edwards College. Signed by Beekman C. Cannon., June 12, 1967.; In Latin. 1 leaf. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Education/Records: Yale: Diploma., 1967. (Box 36, Folder 2)
      Primi honoris academici candidatum ad gradum titulumque artium liberalium baccalaurei ...
    - Employment/Teaching Position: Phillips Academy: Check to Ishem Infirmary Hospital., August 25, 1970. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Employment/Teaching Position: Cheshire Academy: The Cheshire Academy Yearbook., 1970. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      With note and photo from Joe Church, former student, dated 1993. Yearbook contains photos of PM (see index).
    - Education: Yale: Alumnus: From Yale Alumni magazine classnotes. (?)., 1980; Clipping. (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Excerpt from Paul's letter which mentions his partner, Roger, and his opinions on being gay at Yale.
    - Education: Yale: Alumnus: Correspondence with John Groman (?). (PM's reply)., October 26, 1982 and n.d.; Typed and holograph, signed, and typed, signed. 2 items, 3 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      About contributing to Alumni fund. PM's (irate) reply, detailing his giving to gay organizations and MECLA.
    - Education: Yale: Alumnus: Graduate gatherings of Elihu., 1987, 1991. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Education: Yale: Alumnus: PM letter to Yale Alumni Magazine class notes., Summer 1993. (Box 5, Folder 17)
      re having AIDS.
    - Education: Yale: Alumnus: Correspondence Received: Yale graduates respond to PM letter., 1993 (after summer publication). (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Travel(?): Andover: Ephemera: Paper coaster, Andover Inn on the campus of Phillips Academy. (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Education: Phillips Academy: Correspondences Received from Students, 1988-1994. (Box 8, Folder 4)
      From students who attended Andover at or near the time PM attended.
    - Education/Employment: Phillips Academy: Correspondences Received from PM's Students and Colleagues, 1989-1993, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 5)
      PM taught summer school only.
    - Education: Phillips Academy: Correspondences Received from Teachers, 1992-1993. (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Cornelia Fitts, Guy Hughes.
    - Education: Phillips Academy: Correspondences from Persons in Andover (the Town), 1993-1994. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Education: Yale: Personal Letters Received from Fellow Students, 1988-1994. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Employment/Teaching: Milton Academy: Correspondences Received from former Students and Colleagues, 1988-1993. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Employment/Teaching: Correspondences Received: Former Students, 1993. (Box 8, Folder 15)
      Cf. Sutton Hill in Becoming a Man.
  - Subseries 2.3: Relationships
    - Roger Horwitz: RH's dissertation., Another copy. (Box 51, Folder 6)
      See Box 43 folder 7.
    - Roger Horwitz: Notes, etc.: RH to PM., 1977.; 1 typed note. (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Refers to Musical Comedy and Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll manuscripts.
    - Roger Horwitz: Correspondences: Personal letters to PM and RH., 1986. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Roger Horwitz: Memorial Items: Keepsakes and correspondence re funeral and burial arrangements., 1986. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Memorial keepsake with two poems by PM, 40 and My Shirts. Memorial keepsake with inscription from memorial tablet, correspondence re memorial tablet.
    - Roger Horwitz: Memorial Items: Condolence letters., October 1986-November 1987.; 10 items, 15 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Betty Berzon, Alfed Corn, Rob Eichberg, Rudy Kikel, Susan Rankaitis, Lana Remez, Rita Remez, David Schorr, Joey Terrill.
    - Roger Horwitz: Memorial Items: Condolence letters from Madeleine Follain., 1986-1989. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Roger Horwitz: Memorial Items: Condolence letters., December 1986-December 1988. (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Letter from Casenza includes a photo of RH Names Project Quilt panel.
    - Roger Horwitz: Memorial Items: Condolence letters., 1986. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Roger Horwitz: Memorial Items: Condolence letters., 1988. (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Records of donations sent to University of Tennessee Center for Health Sciences in memory of RH. Mentions of Al, Bernice (RH's parents).
    - Roger Horwitz: Memorial Items: Condolence letters., 1986-1989. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Roger Horwitz: Memorial Items: Condolence letters., 1986-1987. (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Includes letter from John Sonsini.
    - Roger Horwitz: Memorial Items: Condolence letters--thinking of Roger. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Roger Horwitz: Memorial Items: Condolence letters., 1990-1992. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Roger Horwitz: Correspondences: Letters from people who made Roger's panel for the Names Project., July 1992. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Stephen Kolzak: Clippings, 1972-1981. (Box 34, Folder 13)
      Photo album from 1972 drama productions, program from 1981 Harvard Club tribute to Jack Lemmon.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Correspondences: Notes. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Card from SK to PM.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Correspondences: Notes., 1988. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Cards from SK to PM and one from PM to SK.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Correspondences: Notes., 1989. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      One card from SK to PM and one card from PM to SK.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Correspondences: Notes., 1990. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Cards from SK to PM.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Correspondences: Letters from friends., 1989. (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Letters from friends to SK and PM. Includes letter from Victor Kenyon Brown, etc.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Correspondences: To PM from Ted Kolzak [father]., September 26, 1989. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Stephen Kolzak: Correspondences: Notes., v.d. (primarily 1989 and 1990) and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
      From PM to SK, SK to PM. From Louis Sherry Box (folder 1 of 2).
    - Stephen Kolzak: Correspondences: Notes., v.d. (primarily 1989-1990) and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 10)
      From PM to SK, SK to PM. From Louis Sherry Box (folder 2 of 2).
    - Stephen Kolzak: Items About: Clippings, etc., 1971-1990. (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Includes letter from Mayor Tom Bradley (November 1, 1985, typed, signed), Jack Lemmon (typed, signed).
    - Stephen Kolzak: Journal, 1987. (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Journal with one leaf inserted.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Photographs, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Professional photographs.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Employment: Clips from television programs' publicity., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Programs: Cheers, Night Court.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Letters Received by Stephen: From friend., January 1990. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Stephen Kolzak: Travel Souvenirs, 1989. (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Greece, Paris, San Francisco. Moved from Louis Sherry Box.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Memorial Items, September 22, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Memorial location card from Forest Lawn Memorial Park.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Memorial Items: Obituaries., 1990. (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Press release. Obituary published in Boston Globe, Hollywood Reporter, etc.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Memorial Items: Memorial program., September 22, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Includes Stephen at the FDA [poem by PM].
    - Stephen Kolzak: Memorial Items: Condolence letters received., 1990-1992. (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Betty Berzon, Buzz Bryan, Tom Capps, Larry Duplechan, Michael Denneny, Robert Eichberg, Alan Fein, Katherine V. Forrest, David Kalmansohn, Rudy Kikel.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Memorial Items: Condolence letters., 1990. (Box 3, Folder 21)
      From: Steve Levitt, John Lithgow, Tim Miller, Michael Nava, Elisabeth Nonas, Torie Osborne, John Preston, Eileen Rankel, Doug Sadownick.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Memorial Items: Condolence letters., 1990. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      From: Christopher (Sands?), Rhonda Pinzer Sherman, Karen Siteman, Mason Sommers, Wendy Weil, The Names Project Staff and others.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Memorial Items: Condolence letters., 1990. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Robert Dawidoff, Dale Reynolds, etc.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Stephen Kolzak Award: Clippings., 1991. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Stephen Kolzak: Stephen Kolzak Award: PM acceptance speech., 1991.; 2 leaves typescript. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      With handwritten notes by PM.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Correspondences: Letters Received from Dolores Snow, Stephen's mother., April 1993. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Stephen Kolzak: Realia: Louis Sherry Box. (Box 35, Folder 1)
      Greeting cards and memorabilia (SK and PM) kept in this Box.
    - Stephen Kolzak: Video Recording of Travels With PM: Hawaii and Venice., January 1989 and May 1989.; 1 videocassette (VHS). (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Stephen Kolzak: Stephen Kolzak Award: Gay and Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation. Awards banquet(?)., April 21, 1991.; 1 video tape. (Box 38, Folder 6)
      Award named for SK given first posthumously to SK and accepted by PM.
    - Estate, Stephen Kolzak and Forest Lawn Paperwork, 1990 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Winston Wilde: Correspondences: Letters to PM and WW., January 1992-1994. (Box 4, Folder 30)
      Includes letter from M[ichael?] Lassell.